<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Help Me With Money! 😱</title>
    <link>https://helpmewith.money/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Help Me With Money! 😱</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://helpmewith.money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/intro/</guid>
      <description>With the steady decline of late-stage capitalism, money management is a popular topic these days. It&amp;rsquo;s no longer enough to have a job in a &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; industry. There are hundreds of websites, books, and podcasts offering tips, techniques, and tricks on how to make your money make money.
But what if good enough is all you want? Navigating the terrain of financial topics when you&amp;rsquo;re content with just getting by is nigh impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addendum I: What do I invest in, and how much?</title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/addendum_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/addendum_one/</guid>
      <description>Up until now, we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed what sort of accounts you should have, but we haven&amp;rsquo;t talked about where you should put your money. That&amp;rsquo;s because this is entirely based on personal choices. There&amp;rsquo;s no one-size-fits-all solution. The advice above is good information to guide you towards your goals, but only you know what those goals are. The savings plans for a twenty-two year old might not be the same plans for a fifty-five year old who is much closer to retirement!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addendum II: Additional resources</title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/addendum_two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/addendum_two/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve read through all of this and are still eager for more information: relax. Everything after this point are either citations for everything described above, or, crazy minutiae when dealing with asset holdings. After getting yourself out of debt, remember that there&amp;rsquo;s more to life than worrying about money. Don&amp;rsquo;t deny your inner self!
  JLCollin&amp;rsquo;s stock series breaks down strategies for handling your assets into digestable chunks. It&amp;rsquo;s very highly recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 1: Pay off all your debt</title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/step_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/step_1/</guid>
      <description>No one is saying that this first step is easy, but it is undoubtedly the most important move to make: pay off any debt you hold immediately.
As suggested by the section on compound interest above, credit card companies charge astronomically high interest rates. That $10,000 purchase you made could cost you an additional $2,500 at best if you don&amp;rsquo;t pay it back on time. The easiest way to not owe additional money is to not spend money that you don&amp;rsquo;t have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 2: Maximize 401(k) contributions</title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/step_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/step_2/</guid>
      <description>With debt out of the way (hooray!), it&amp;rsquo;s time to introduce a few more terms:
Taxable accounts These are accounts which are taxed every year at tax season. They include savings accounts, stock market funds, and so on. Every year, when your accounts grow due to interest, you must pay taxes on that profit.
Tax-deferred accounts These are accounts most commonly associated with retirement plans with difficult names such as 401(k) or IRA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 3: Maximize your savings</title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/step_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/step_3/</guid>
      <description>You have no debt and you&amp;rsquo;ve started some basic saving for retirement. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to build up your emergency account.
This account should only be used for unexpected expenditures, such as repairs to a bicycle, medical bills, or if you suddenly find yourself unemployed. A good rule of thumb is to save about six to twelve months of your monthly gross income. For example, if every month you spend $3,000, have an account somewhere with at least $9,000 stored in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 4: Maximize IRA contributions</title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/step_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/step_4/</guid>
      <description>With your 401(k) steadily growing, you might think you&amp;rsquo;re all set for retirement.
But you&amp;rsquo;re not! Saving for retirement is just about the best thing you can do, because you never know what the future will hold. Because of the magic power of compound interest, the more you save (and the earlier you save it), the more money you can expect to collect when you need to.
To that end, once you&amp;rsquo;ve set up a savings account, you can start funding an IRA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 5: Contribute to other taxable accounts</title>
      <link>https://helpmewith.money/step_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helpmewith.money/step_5/</guid>
      <description>If, and only if, you&amp;rsquo;ve completed all the other steps, you&amp;rsquo;ve somehow achieved the near-impossible, and you can begin to consider contributing to other accounts. Growth on these sorts of accounts are taxed every year, but, unlike retirement accounts, you can use that money whenever you want, not just when you retire.
What other types of investments are there? Plenty. Although you could choose to invest in individual stocks, a much more sound financial strategy would involve investing in &amp;ldquo;a stock of stocks,&amp;rdquo; or a mutual fund.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>